Olga Bolshchikova

UX Designer

I am a UX designer with an international background and I4+ years of experience in graphic design. When designing I strive to achieve a harmonious blend of functionality and aesthetics and create solutions that are valuable for both users and business.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Visual Designer

BlueApple Design, Menlo Park, CA

Apr 2016-Present

 Created banners, icons, designed interactive e-books and white papers by following corporate brand identity and visual guidelines

UX/UI Design Apprentice

Designlab, San Francisco, CA

Jan 2017-Nov 2017

- Performed UX design process of discover, define, design, and test
- Conducted user research to reveal insights and gain empathy; synthesized findings and formed UX strategy
- Created key design deliverables such as empathy maps, personas, storyboards, sitemaps, user flows, wireframes
- Produced user interface design for responsive websites (e-commerce product and non-profit organization) and mobile apps for iOS and Android (banking and augmented reality)
- · Conducted usability testing and iterated on design based on feedback

Freelance Visual/UI Designer

Safe Drive Systems, New York, NY

Mar 2015-Mar 2016

- Designed user-centered landing pages, ads, e-brochures, and flyers from design concept to completion
- Created presentations for potential car buyers in 60+ dealerships; resulted in 18% increase in product sales
- Redesigned website blog for better user interaction and SEO optimization, increasing blog traffic by over 50%

Freelance Graphic Designer

IMR, New York, NY

Sept 2014-Aug 2015

- Executed redesign, layout, and production of "IMR Review," the corporate magazine, and multi-page journalistic reports
- Implemented image manipulations, photo retouching, and vector graphics to improve visual perception and quality of the magazine

Sr. Graphic/Web Designer

Integral LLC, Yekaterinburg, Russia

Dec 2000-May 2014

- Supervised design, layout, and production of 5 monthly scientific magazines and 3 newspapers with a circulation of 25K+
- Reduced ~30% of client printing costs by interviewing and selecting the best offset/digital print vendor

- http://bolshchikova.com
- olga.bolshchikova@gmail.com
- (347) 873-7216
- San Jose, CA

SKILLS

UX Design

- User Research
- Information Architecture
- Wireframing
- Interaction Design
- UI Design
- Prototyping
- Usability Testing

Visual Design

- Layout
- Typography
- Branding
- Image Manipulation

TOOLS

- Sketch
- Photoshop
- InDesign
- Illustrator
- InVision / Marvel
- Balsamiq / Axure
- Zeplin
- Acrobat
- HTML5 / CSS3
- Keynote / PowerPoint

EDUCATION

UX Academy

DesignLab Nov 2017

• UX/UI Design Fundamentals

Bloc.io Dec 2015

 Bachelor of Science (BS), Engineering Physics

Ural Federal University, Russia

TRAINING

• UX & Web Design Master Course
Udemy

March 2017

• Human-Computer Interaction

Coursera Aug 2014

HTML & CSS

Codecademy May 2013